# Lamisa Saadat

 $\frac{647-376-6478 \mid \underline{ls.lamisa12@gmail.com} \mid \underline{linkedin.com/in/lamisaadat} \mid \underline{github.com/LamiSaadat} \mid \underline{lamisaadat.com} \mid \underline{Toronto, ON, Canada} \mid \underline{lamisaadat.com} \mid \underline{lamisaadat.com$ 

## Profile

Managing the lifecycle of digital products for 4 years, I had the opportunity to test and provide feedback to multiple developers on a range of apps. Always interested in the work behind the scenes, I took up the challenge of learning web development myself. In the next phase of my career, I look forward to blending my product management experiences with my new-found passion to deliver meaningful solutions for the user.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Working Kowledge: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Ionic Framework, Web APIs, REST APIs, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Prisma ORM, Version Control (Git, Github)

**Exposed To**: Redux, Python, Flask, Django, TypeScript, Angular.js, Bootstrap, Styled Components, AWS, Test-driven Development (Jest)

#### EXPERIENCE

### Frontend Engineer, Freelance

 $Feb\ 2023-Present$ 

Tidey Mitchener Consulting

Remote, Toronto, ON

- Implementing a mobile-first and responsive front-end with Ionic and Angular
- Creating high-performance communication channels with the backend to display data dynamically
- Integrating external platforms such as payment and email automation to enable a seamless user experience

# Digital Services Senior Executive (Product Manager)

Feb 2017 – Feb 2021

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Banglalink
  - $\bullet$  Developed strategy, and execution processes, and defined core metrics to drive business through apps and value-added services and maintained daily revenue above USD 75k
  - Drove product development in collaboration with the technical teams including networking, charging & billing, database administration
  - Coordinated with cross-functional teams including engineering, UX/UI, sales, marketing, and customer success simultaneously to formulate effective online and offline distribution strategies for products
  - Monitored and improved customer journeys of 100+ third-party services which included health and education applications
  - Launched a music platform and gained the number 1 title in Google Play Store in only 5 days
  - $\bullet$  Analyzed quantitative and qualitative data to monitor service progress and identify opportunities to increase product portfolio revenue by 20% each year

#### Projects

#### Blog API | Repo | Node, Express, PostgreSQL, Prisma

Nov 2022

• A Hashnode-inspired blog API where users can register, log in, follow other users and perform CRUD operations on posts. Users can also save posts as drafts, like them, and comment on them. Users can also follow other users.

# Dev's Board | Repo | React, SASS, Node, Express, MySQL, Knex.js

June 2022

• A responsive web application where users can create mood boards consisting of images and color palettes based on a keyword. User boards are saved to the database and can be deleted.

## EDUCATION

#### **BrainStation**

Toronto, ON

Diploma in Web Development

Apr 2022 - Jul 2022

North South University

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Bachelor of Business Administration

2012 - 2016